I'm so sorry for taking so long to arrive.
Is this person...
Episode 11 "The Empty Princess Lives"
Is that really Anastasia?
Yes. Her hair and manner
of dress are different...
but there's no mistake.
Wait. That voice!
Marie! Is that you, Marie?
Yes.
Sister... it's you, isn't it?
It is.
She really is alive.
What's going on?
So you're Count Granado.
Release Marie from the betrothal immediately!
If all you want is someone to give you
noble children, then I should suffice!
Wha—?
S-Sister, it isn't that you want
to marry Lord Kyros, is it?
Of course not!
He's a piece of trash who would buy
a woman's womb with money and power.
T-Trash?
Lady Anastasia, why have you
appeared now, after all this time?
B-Because...
There seem to be some other
circumstances at work here.
I'll send word to Norman.
For now, please come to the castle.
But I...
It's all right, Big Sister.
Sparkling
Now you're sparklingly clean, Sister!
Y-Yeah.
Is this your room, Marie?
It's lovely!
I'm sorry, Sister.
You must be tired.
We could talk tomorrow
after you've slept a bit.
No.
I have a responsibility to talk about this.
I... want to apologize.
I've never been able to protect you, Marie.
Sister...
How far back should I go...
Back when you had a fever...
That night, when Grandmother
Sasha scolded me...
Grandmother?
Marie has fallen asleep.
Leave the rest to me.
Yes.
Languages from so many countries...
That's because people from many
countries have sent them.
This is... Father's name, isn't it?
Why are you signing it, Grandmother?
Because everyone is born suited for
some things and not for others.
That's true. Like me.
I'm not smart like Marie.
Anastasia.
You possess an inventiveness
that others do not.
It's an ability that will not
shine through academics alone.
Grandmother!
Despite appearances, Gregor performs
marvelously on musical instruments.
That path would have
actually been the boy's—
M-Mama! Papa!
Don't call them here!
B-But...
It's already far too late.
In our era, we could not
choose how to live our lives.
But the era you two will live
through will be different.
I hope that each of you will make use of
your strengths and do work that you love.
That is my only wish.
My mother has passed away.
What will happen to us?
Marie!
How much did you learn from my mother?
Do you understand Flarian?
I-I've only learned a little.
She must have caught Marie's illness.
Marie killed Lady Sasha!
It couldn't possibly have been Marie's fault.
But ever since that day, Mama has
stopped seeing Marie as her daughter.
Marie.
Wouldn't you like to try attending school?
What?
It's a town school,
but I hear they teach the current
usage of foreign languages there.
You like to study, don't you?
Yes, I do... but won't it
cost money for me to attend?
It's all right. That's not something
you need to worry about.
But the servants say they haven't received
their wages for over two months.
That's because there's no
need to pay the incompetent.
But...
I am the lord here. Will you defy me?
You see? Women who get a taste of
education are so quick to rebel.
Entirely unendearing.
That's right.
You are a charmless, unlovely woman.
I am... not lovely.
You are ugly and impudent.
You'd never survive anywhere else.
The least you could do is study and
be useful to the lord of this region.
Papa!
Why would you say such awful things?
Everything your father said is
correct, my lovely Anastasia.
Marie, you understand, don't you?
You know that, though everyone loves
Anastasia, you are not like her.
Yes.
Marie...
Dismissing the servants will
take care of your tuition.
You will do the housework.
And we'll sell your dresses, too.
Yes.
Very good.
If you obey me like this, it does
grant you a tiny bit of charm.
Yes, Father.
That day, Marie's life completely changed.
She was made to work from
dawn until deepest night.
In the blink of an eye, Marie
became tattered and ragged.
Mama, why do you treat Marie like that?
What choice do I have?
That unlucky, sinister red hair...
Lady Sasha was cursed by that child and died.
What are you saying? What does
Grandmother have to do with this?
Ah, but then there's you, Anastasia.
This beautiful blonde hair
and those blue eyes...
It's as if Lady Sasha has returned to us.
It really is as if she's alive.
Mama... I'm alive.
Marie was in rags, but she was
allowed into the outside world,
while I was like a doll,
trapped inside the house.
Confound it!
Why aren't more significant
figures proposing marriage?
Won't Marie be marrying anyone?
What man would ever want
to take her as his wife?
But you're different.
As a noble's daughter,
you will fulfill the vital duty of
marriage like a good girl, won't you?
Yes. It's wonderful!
The truth is, I'd like to try
opening up a shop in the capital.
But...
all that I'm permitted to do is
be an obedient, beautiful doll.
Crap! Where did she run off to?
That stuck-up wench... she threw herself in!
Looks like I tricked him!
Moron! Take that!
Anastasia threw herself
into the river and died.
What are you doing?
His eyes...
What's your name?
A-Ana...
Arthur! Got a problem with that?
This kid seems to have some spirit.
What happened? What are you
doing in a place like this?
U-Um, well, I was...
I made up a story then and there.
I lied and said I'd been sold off.
Old Man Norman said he'd let me
stay at his house for a while.
C-Could it be... Do you make clothes here?
Yes. I am a button artisan, after all.
Though, I'm as good as retired now.
Are you serious, old man?
Make me your apprentice!
What?
I like making clothes! See? I made these!
This is...
Yes, indeed. They're small
for a man's clothes, but...
That's because they're for women to
dress as men! It's a hobby of mine.
T-To dress as men?
Of course, I can make regular clothes, too.
Opening up a shop in the capital is my dream!
I don't take apprentices.
I don't have a home or anywhere else to go.
I'll take care of odd jobs or whatever else!
I want to be reborn here and
make my dream come true!
Please!
You can stay here at my house.
As for my work...
you'll have to watch and learn.
Every day was like a dream.
Hey there, Norman. How have you been?
Sorry to cut straight to the point, but
I'd like you to set this jewel in a ring.
This is an impressively high-quality gem.
The spelling for the engraving on the ring
is written on the request form, but...
That won't be a problem. I'll have
my apprentice read it to me later.
Oh, you've taken an apprentice?
I guess the workshop is safe, then.
Arthur, this is a national treasure that
Count Granado obtained through Prince Luiphon.
Since you're studying the craft,
you should take a look, too.
It's beautiful.
I hear he's been searching for a striking
red stone to match the color of his bride's hair.
Red hair?
This ring is intended for the younger sister
of his betrothed, who died in an accident.
Inscription: Marie
Marie?
"The dream is over."
Reality whispered those words into my ear.
Marie?
Why?
Why is my big sister the only
one who gets to be happy?
Why do I have to take her place?
I will never forgive my
sister for running away!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
There's really no possible way?
No, I don't feel well.
The letter from the count said that
I was to bring you along, didn't it?
All right. I'll apologize to the count.
Because I don't know what I
should do... my body won't move.
I know that Marie must be suffering.
I want to protect her, but...
You are the one person I most want to
be able to walk your own path in life.
So this time, I will protect you!
Please...
Give me the courage...
And so you came to this castle...
Yes.
Marie, I'm sorry it took me so long.
From now on, I'll protect you.
Sister...
Yes? Come in.
Have you just about finished?
Yes. Thank you for letting
the two of us speak alone.
Sister, I'm happy you feel the way you do.
But...
You have it all wrong!
The two of us really are in love!
Dazed...
What?
Master, why is your face
that of a lovelorn maiden?
Suspicious...
Marie, he's deceiving you.
Why would you think that?
Because saying things is easy!
Especially for unscrupulous adults!
It's unfathomable that
you would doubt my love!
If money and power could
make things go as I wanted,
I'd have abducted her the day I met her!
I'd destroy the Shaderan family for hurting
Marie and go off an a journey with her!
From morning 'til night,
I'd never let her go!
If this isn't love, then why would I have
bought a body pillow? You dunderhead!
Marie is Life
Repulsed...
I'm worried about this man
in a different way now.
Master, I believe that will suffice.
Everyone is thoroughly horrified.
All of this began because I wrote the
wrong name on my offer of marriage.
I'm sorry.
What?
But the love I feel for Marie is real.
No matter what hardships
may rain down upon us,
I will spend my life protecting her.
I want to become Marie's family.
Even I understand the
desire to treasure family.
Can you take responsibility for those words?
If you can't, I'll steal Marie back from you.
Yes, I swear it.
I swear that the two of
us will find happiness.
Marie, you've been loved, as you should be.
You've been smiling here,
in the place where you belong.
Yes!
That little girl I needed to
save is gone now, isn't she?
Sister.
Everyone, thank you for
gathering at my request.
Um...
The truth is, this is something I
wanted my sister to hear as well.
Something you want me to hear?
It's about Father's crimes.
Sister, have you ever seen them?
The prose or letters that Grandmother
or I wrote in Father's place...
Now that you mention it, I have seen them.
After hearing what you said, I was certain.
It isn't just the kingdom's tongue...
Father can't use Flarian either.
What? Is that a crime?
Yes.
Since official documents are written and
exchanged in Flarian, the language of the nobility,
managing territory and overseeing its
people would be difficult without it.
But unlike when Grandmother was here,
Father didn't notify the kingdom.
Instead, he simply had me
write documents on his behalf.
Forgery of official documents and
abandonment of his duties as lord...
Those are my father's crimes, aren't they?
Exactly.
As a noble, who oversees the welfare
of his people, he has utterly failed.
His abuse of Lady Marie and the others
shows his failure as a human being.
The baron wanted to hide
his own incompetence,
so he set up Marie as his
stand-in in an illegal manner.
Then he used rags and
tatters to chain Marie down
and exploit her for
the sake of his noble house.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know that doing a lord's work in their
stead without the crown's permission was a crime.
Even if you had known, you couldn't
have refused in that situation.
I've already checked and found that
you bear no responsibility in this.
We'll be sure to protect you!
Marie, you have the right to decide what
will happen to the House of Shaderan.
Marie, please tell us what
it is you wish to do.
Until now, I've always run away.
But now I've learned that my decisions can
bring happiness and unhappiness to others.
I can't pretend not to see
these things any longer.
I will face the truth and look
upon it with my own eyes.
Please allow me to make my
decision after I've done that.
Understood.
Marie.
After all, I'm of the mind to hit
my parents with one good wallop!
M-Marie?
You've grown quite strong, haven't you?
Let's go...
to the House of Shaderan!
This is Anastasia.
Now that we sisters are together,
there's only one thing for us to do, right?
Next time, "It's Time to Settle This."
Episode 12 "It's Time to Settle This"
Let's go, Marie!